<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: quotes | thoughts in plain text]]></title>
  <link href="http://lc0.github.io/blog/categories/quotes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lc0.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-27T01:50:29+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://lc0.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sergii Khomenko]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steal Like an Artist: 10 Things Nobody Told You About Being Creative]]></title>
    <link href="http://lc0.github.io/blog/2013/06/08/steal-like-an-artist-10-things-nobody-told-you-about-being-creative/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-08T23:13:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lc0.github.io/blog/2013/06/08/steal-like-an-artist-10-things-nobody-told-you-about-being-creative</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Initially I thought about writing technical posts here, but in the titles of the blog there also are words “my thoughts about .. people”.
So, I’m gonna add some blog posts about interesting books.<br /></p>

<p>About format: I don’t like to write down any reviews or other similar things. Currently I use my kindle to read the most books I have.
Also I like to highlight some quotes while reading a book with a kindle. I’m not sure, that independent quotes could represent any full
picture of a book, but anyway I’m gonna just share my quotes like points of the book. And if you’re interested you could try to connect some of them and take decision to read it or to skip.<br /></p>

<p>So, the first book I’m gonna open this sort of posts here is <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13099738-steal-like-an-artist">Steal Like an Artist: 10 Things Nobody Told You About Being Creative</a></p>

<p><img src="http://austinkleon.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/3d-Steal-Like-an-Artist-NYT.jpg" alt="Steal Like an Artist: 10 Things Nobody Told You About Being Creative" />
<!--more--></p>

<p><blockquote><p>“Immature poets imitate; mature poets steal; bad poets deface what they take, and good poets make it into something better, or at least something different. The good poet welds his theft into a whole of feeling which is unique, utterly different from that from which it was torn.” —T. S. Eliot</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Nothing is completely original. It’s right there in the Bible: “There is nothing new under the sun.” (Ecclesiastes 1:9)</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>As the French writer André Gide put it, “Everything that needs to be said has already been said. But, since no one was listening, everything must be said again.”</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>The German writer Goethe said, “We are shaped and fashioned by what we love.”</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>There’s an economic theory out there that if you take the incomes of your five closest friends and average them, the resulting number will be pretty close to your own income.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>You have to be curious about the world in which you live. Look things up. Chase down every reference. Go deeper than anybody else—that’s how you’ll get ahead.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Remember: Even The Beatles started as a cover band. Paul McCartney has said, “I emulated Buddy Holly, Little Richard, Jerry Lee Lewis, Elvis. We all did.” McCartney and his partner John Lennon became one of the greatest songwriting teams in history, but as McCartney recalls, they only started writing their own songs “as a way to avoid other bands being able to play our set.” As Salvador Dalí said, “Those who do not want to imitate anything, produce nothing.”</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>cartoonist Gary Panter say, “If you have one person you’re influenced by, everyone will say you’re the next whoever. But if you rip off a hundred people, everyone will say you’re so original!”</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>The manifesto is this: Draw the art you want to see, start the business you want to run, play the music you want to hear, write the books you want to read, build the products you want to use—do the work you want to see done.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Step one, “do good work,” is incredibly hard. There are no shortcuts. Make stuff every day. Know you’re going to suck for a while. Fail. Get better.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>“Distance and difference are the secret tonic of creativity. When we get home, home is still the same. But something in our mind has been changed, and that changes everything.” —Jonah Lehrer</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Your brain gets too comfortable in your everyday surroundings. You need to make it uncomfortable. You need to spend some time in another land, among people that do things differently than you. Travel makes the world look new, and when the world looks new, our brains work harder.</p></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
