<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startups | thoughts in plain text]]></title>
  <link href="http://lc0.github.io/blog/categories/startups/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lc0.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-23T00:16:51+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://lc0.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sergii Khomenko]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building and scaling a company. Linkedin story.]]></title>
    <link href="http://lc0.github.io/blog/2013/07/26/building-and-scaling-a-company-linkedin-story/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-26T00:28:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lc0.github.io/blog/2013/07/26/building-and-scaling-a-company-linkedin-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was always interested in technology stack of large-scale startups. It’s quite interesting to follow the
evolutions of the company during not so long periods. From one point, it’s interesting to follow changes of technologies,
but much more interesting are reasons which have led to such decisions. So today I’m going to share the story of Linkedin told by
<a href="https://twitter.com/jaykreps">Jay Kreps</a>, Principle Staff Engineer at LinkedIn during the InfoQ conference.</p>

<p><center><iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/24263581?rel=0" frameborder="0" width="597" height="486" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC;border-width:1px 1px 0;margin-bottom:5px" allowfullscreen> </iframe></center>
<!--more-->
Jay describes the evolution of the startup’s architecture from the simplest iteration
<img src="http://image.slidesharecdn.com/untitled-130715145706-phpapp01/95/slide-10-638.jpg" alt="simplest" /><br />
to more distributed with more elements like voldemort and hadoop
<img src="http://image.slidesharecdn.com/untitled-130715145706-phpapp01/95/slide-11-638.jpg" alt="second iteration with voldemort and hadoop" /><br />
and even more with Apache Kafka, messaging system, and Espresso, key-value database.
<img src="http://image.slidesharecdn.com/untitled-130715145706-phpapp01/95/slide-12-638.jpg" alt="voldemort, hadoop, kafka, espreso" /><br /></p>

<p>The main idea Jay tells us, is to try to use simple, cheap and scalable primitives to be able to re-use
one infrastructure for different purposes. Another idea is to have all expensive operation asynchronously,
because all, that could fail, is going to fail and all front-end would follow the failing backend.
Hard things should be executed offline, because they are safe and cheap, while offline.<br /></p>

<p>Another big line of the presentation is transition from monolithic application architecture to service oriented architecture.
The big idea reminds me of the principle of <a href="http://12factor.net/">The Twelve-Factor App</a>
<img src="http://image.slidesharecdn.com/untitled-130715145706-phpapp01/95/slide-21-638.jpg" alt="software-as-a-service at Linkedin" /><br />
The main advantage of such methodology is ability to easily iterate over versions, to be quite independent inside the service and
to re-use some primitives of the infrastructure. By the way, deciding to move forward with
software-as-a-service methodology, we need to understand the problem of the granularity of a service. Also about among-server communication,
within Linkedin they changed a couple of integration layers started from  HTTP + serializable Java, after Protocol Buffer + TCP and finally REST + JSON.</p>

<p>There is also a good explanation of the idea to have a code owner and treating the code as property.
Discussed main points of interaction within team and other aspects of agile at scale.</p>

<p>The full version of the video could be found by <a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/linkedin-architecture-stack">link</a><br />
Another post about large-scale architecture of startups: <a href="/blog/2013/02/13/scaling-pinterest/">Scaling Pinterest</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Actionable customer development]]></title>
    <link href="http://lc0.github.io/blog/2013/04/09/actionable-customer-development/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-09T00:32:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lc0.github.io/blog/2013/04/09/actionable-customer-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently found a good presentation about actionable customer development for startups. Yes, it sounds like some buzzwords, 
but in presentations you could find the first stage of every idea - validation. The most interesting part of the workshop
is recommendations about performing correct user interviews to validate the idea.</p>

<p>Usually it’s a very first big mistake of funders, because we so much believe in our idea. We love it so much, that are ready to ask 
the wrong questions just to find some confirmation of our ideas. But much better to ask correct questions and to find the real user
problems or even pains, than just to work on the problem nobody has. </p>

<p>Fail fast! Fail cheap!</p>

<p><center><iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/18229425?rel=0" frameborder="0" width="597" height="486" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC;border-width:1px 1px 0;margin-bottom:5px" allowfullscreen> </iframe></center></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling Pinterest]]></title>
    <link href="http://lc0.github.io/blog/2013/02/13/scaling-pinterest/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-13T01:12:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://lc0.github.io/blog/2013/02/13/scaling-pinterest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Interesting video from Surge 2012 conference by guys from Pinterest. Yash Nelapati and Marty Weiner tell the story
of changes of the startup’s infrastructure from early days and when Pinterest became one of the biggest website.
Interesting to follow changes of technologies, especially withing such small group of engineers.</p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dSk-SWLJ2g0"></iframe></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[product design: features and simplicity]]></title>
    <link href="http://lc0.github.io/blog/2012/10/21/product-design-features-and-simplicity/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T15:42:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lc0.github.io/blog/2012/10/21/product-design-features-and-simplicity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><center><iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/14814757?rel=0" frameborder="0" width="597" height="486" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC;border-width:1px 1px 0;margin-bottom:5px" allowfullscreen> </iframe></center></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[notes from idcee 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://lc0.github.io/blog/2012/10/20/notes-from-idcee-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-20T10:34:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://lc0.github.io/blog/2012/10/20/notes-from-idcee-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://cloudessa.com/">Cloudessa</a> - security in the cloud, cloud based solution for security that removes the headaches of maintaining enterprise RADIUS servers. It provides reliable and secure AAA. It is FISMA, PCI, FIPS-compliant. One of the interesting features are 2-factor authorizations and google-sites-based wi-fi auth, when you can allow access only for people from your corporate domain.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.inventarium.mobi/">Inventarium</a> - interesting mobile feedback system with integration for iOS, Android and Windows Phone.
Free for first 1000 users, after - $49/month.</p>

<p><a href="http://kuznech.com/">Kuznech</a> - the winner of startup competition at IDCEE2012. Image processing toolkit with wide range of different functions.
Michael(CEO) said, that they have different technologies, from morphology-based image similarity to image retrieval and search among images.
Also he said, that they were working for a while on it and have some US patents on their technologies. I can’t find any patents dedicated to Kuztech like a company, but there are some patents from their Chief Scientist <a href="https://www.google.com/search?tbo=p&amp;tbm=pts&amp;hl=en&amp;q=ininventor:%22Alexander+Valencia-Campo%22">Alexander Valencia-Campo</a>. Anyway, they have a really strong <a href="http://kuznech.com/about/">team</a> with solid experience in the area.</p>

<p><a href="http://gossipteller.com/">GossipTeller</a> - anonymous service to share and discover gossips about people, events and other local things. They do not use
exist social feeds like twitter of facebook, you can create your news anonymously. The team has nice iOS application and some traction from US students.</p>

<p>Sometimes, don’t have any plans to meet someone, and just meet interesting and smart people, on the IDCEE it was a case with Marvin Liao, Commercial Director, EMEA Expansion Markets at Yahoo! Inc. Thanks to Alex Barrera I’ve met Marvin, we had an interesting conversation on a/b testing, fashion startups, facebook’s stocks and lots of other topics.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
